<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>Memorias de un Informático</description>
    <link>
    </link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Introduction to Machine Learning</title>
        
          <description>    &lt;p&gt;Machine learning has got a lot of popularity in our modern world due to the development
    of the internet, the storage of large amounts of data, etc. Most of
    the nowadays technologies are more or less related to the automation
    of learning, some examples could be spam detection, speech recognition,
    image classifying, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Machine learning itself is a subfield of computer science which allows computers to
    learn by themselves. The term was first coined in 1959 by IBM, however it never
    gained as much popularity as it has today.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Machine learning has probably earned that much popularity due to the
    fact that more data was created in the last 2 years than in the whole
    history, and also, that as we can see in top500.org the computers are
    exponentially getting better which allows us to execute more complex
    operations faster.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;It is strictly related to
    several fields such as data analysis, data mining and maths. In order
    to fully understand machine learning, a basis of algebra and statistics
    is needed.
    Here, you can find several resources for learning algebra;
    https://my.mindnode.com/9GQnwWMBYXMe1XjUD8G21qpxiyz5B4MraPtL8xyy
    And here, for statistics:
    https://my.mindnode.com/7cSLjj5rauAnjWT1zHqEmqGkixvoVWaMz8C7Q2aW).&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/TV9nQwF.png&quot; alt=&quot;XVOEjvl.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;In machine learning we can classify the tasks into three categories,
    we will see examples of each of them.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Supervised learning: we provide some example inputs (called training data)
    and the desired outputs. The model has to make predictions while being
    trained and corrected if they are wrong. The training process will end
    whenever the desired level of accuracy is achieved.
    Some examples are Decision Trees and Logistic Regressions. Find more info
    about them here:
    https://www.analyticsvidhya.com/blog/2016/04/complete-tutorial-tree-based-modeling-scratch-in-python/
    https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logistic_regression&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Unsupervised learning: we can’t make predictions as we don’t know the 
    result. We can get the model by deducing structures found in the input data 
    where some general rules could be found. Some examples are K-means and 
    the Apriori algorithm. Find more info here:
    https://en.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning/lecture/93VPG/k-means-algorithm
    https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apriori_algorithm&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Semi-supervised learning: as you can imagine it’s just the combination 
    of supervised and unsupervised learning, you have a desired problem but
     the model has to learn the structures as well as making predictions. Some
     examples are classification and regression.
    https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classification
    https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regression_analysis&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/HKtMPm5.png&quot; alt=&quot;tQuwb4G.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;An algorithm is a sequence of actions that will be performed in order.
     They can be used for calculation, data processing and automated 
    reasoning.
    For you to understand you can think of a recipe, you have several steps 
    that you have to complete in order.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;When we get here things start to get a bit harder and if you want to 
    fully understand how everything works you will need to know algebra 
    and statistics, however, if you just want to have a general knowledge 
    and understand the basics you will be fine with this tut.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Algorithms can be divided by the learning style or the similarity in 
    form/function. Here we will categorize them by similarity (how they 
    work). I also have to say that this is a bit off sometimes as some 
    algorithms can be found in different categories depending on your source.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;First of all I would like to show you a cheat sheet with the most 
    important algorithms that we will see:
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/v6zzgnT.png&quot; alt=&quot;v6zzgnT.png&quot; /&gt;
    Source: https://machinelearningmastery.com&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Starting from the top we see the Deep Learning Algorithms, 
    they are used to create complex neural networks, most of the methods 
    are semi-supervised, large datasets are provided.
    Some important algorithms are the Deep Boltzmann Machine (DBM),
     the Deep Belief Networks (DBM), the Convolutional Neural Network (CNN) 
    and Stacked Auto-encoders.
    It is used a lot for computer vision and speech recognition, they excell
    in image, audio and text data. However, as they need a lot of data it is 
    not suitable for every possible scenario, they also require a lot of 
    computer resources.
    This is one of my favourites so you will probably see some tutorials in 
    the future if I manage to fight my laziness xD&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Trhb5Aq.png&quot; alt=&quot;Trhb5Aq.png&quot; /&gt;
    Source: https://catalystsecure.com&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Neural networks are inspired by the structure of biological neural 
    networks, they are usually used for regression and classification problems 
    but they can be used in a million case scenarios. Neural networks and Deep 
    Learning are usually mixed up, if you want to take it easy you can imagine 
    that Deep Neural Networks are a more “complex” Neural Network, they 
    have more layers and it is more efficient than the “old-school” Neural Networks.
    Some important algorithms are Perceptron, Back-Propagation, The 
    Hopfield Network and the Radial Basis Function Network (RBFN).&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/lBg3qko.png&quot; alt=&quot;lBg3qko.png&quot; /&gt;
    Source: aircto.com&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;The next one that we find is Ensemble Methods (also known as 
    Classification Trees), classifiers are constructed and then new data 
    points are classified by taking a weighted vote of their predictions. 
    It’s like creating weaker models which are independently trained and 
    then combined together to make the final prediction.
    They perform well in practice, they are scalable and robust, they are 
    unlikely to overfit too (be trained too much). Some big algorithms are
    Random Forests and Gradient Boosted Regression Trees (GBRT).&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/CdQMDvQ.png&quot; alt=&quot;CdQMDvQ.png&quot; /&gt;
    Source: http://magizbox.com&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;In Regression Algorithms a relationship between variables is
    created and refined by measuring the error produced in the predictions 
    of the model. Some important ones are Linear regression and Logistic 
    Regression. You can find some examples of these types of regression here: 
    http://magizbox.com/training/machinelearning/site/model_regression/&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/TIcU6nM.png&quot; alt=&quot;TIcU6nM.png&quot; /&gt;
    Source: http://magizbox.com&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Regularization is just an extension to the regression methods, the only
     difference is that it penalizes the models based on their complexity 
    favoring simpler models. They are better at generalizing. They are
    popular, powerful and simple. Some examples are Ridge Regression, 
    Least Absolute Shrinkage and Selection Operator (LASSO), Elastic Net 
    and Least-Angle Regression (LARS).&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Clustering, like regression, describes the class of problem and class of methods.
    A set of objects is grouped in groups called clusters. Some examples are k-Means,
    k-Medians, Expectation Maximisation (EM) and Hierarchical Clustering.
    Here you can see an example of clustering with K-means: http://magizbox.com/training/machinelearning/site/model_clustering/&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/4MNW1BH.png&quot; alt=&quot;4MNW1BH.png&quot; /&gt;
    Source: http://www.kdnuggets.com&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Dimensionally Reduction, like clustering methods, seeks and exploits
     the inherent structure in the data, however, this time it is unsupervised or 
    the data is described with less information. It is useful for visualizing data 
    or simplifying it (which can be later used in a supervised learning method). 
    Some examples are Principal component analysis (PCA), Kernel PCA,
     Graph-based kernel PCA, Linear discriminant analysis (LDA) and Generalized 
    discriminant analysis (GDA).
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/wM6TLuh.png&quot; alt=&quot;wM6TLuh.png&quot; /&gt;
    Source: http://www.bogotobogo.com&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Association Rule Learning Algorithms are kind of self-explanatory, 
    they extract rules that best explain the relationship between variables in data. 
    These rules can discover important associations that can be exploited. There are 
    two very important algorithms in this category: The Apriori Algorithm and the Eclat 
    Algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Bayesian Algorithms: they use the Bayes’ Theorem, it describes the probability
     of an event based on prior knowledge of conditions related to the event. Some 
    examples are Naive Bayes, Gaussian Naive Bayes, Multinomial Naive Bayes, 
    Averaged One-Dependence Estimators (AODE), Bayesian Belief Network (BBN) and 
    Bayesian Network (BN).&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/ojyQZKp.png&quot; alt=&quot;ojyQZKp.png&quot; /&gt;
    Source: https://www.analyticsvidhya.com&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;In Decision Tree Algorithms the model is constructed by the decisions 
    taken which are based on the values of attributes in the data. The model 
    resembles a tree and includes all possible outcomes, consequences, resource 
    costs and utility.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/omoPfYh.png&quot; alt=&quot;muAM0uE.png&quot; /&gt;
    Source: http://www.kdnuggets.com/&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Finally we find Instance Based Algorithms; this learning model is a 
    decision problem with instances or examples of training data that are deemed 
    important or required to the model. They usually build up databases of example 
    data and then they are compared to new data using a similarity measure with 
    the aim of creating the best match and in conclusion the best prediction. They 
    are also called memory-based methods and winner-take-all methods. Some 
    examples are k-Nearest Neighbor (kNN), Learning Vector Quantization (LVQ), 
    Self-Organizing Map (SOM) and Locally Weighted Learning (LWL).&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;In a future tutorial I will tell you a methodology for choosing the best algorithm 
    for your problem, for now I would be happy if you understood everything.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Here you can download a pdf with most of the algorithms, it is pretty useful as
     it tells you the code in python and in R (however I know you guys and I’m sure 
    you will go straight for the python code hehe :P ). Note that it doesn’t use Tensorflow.
    https://discuss.analyticsvidhya.com/t/download-full-cheatsheet-on-machine-learning-algorithms/4063&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/GaclayZ.png&quot; alt=&quot;yizMpKj.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Last of all, I would like to introduce you to some tools/frameworks. I have to say
    that machine learning is a field which is experiencing a lot of big changes lately, 
    so please if you are reading this in the future bare with me and make a quick google 
    search to make sure this is still valid.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;The best of all is that there are many open source software so you don’t have to 
    worry about payments. In my opinion the best tool at the moment is Tensorflow,
    however, here you can find more options for you to choose.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/YPxOIVr.png&quot; alt=&quot;YPxOIVr.png&quot; /&gt;
    Tensorflow was developed by Google with its initial release in 2015. It is a very 
    powerful tool which has compatibility with most CPUs and GPUs. It supports
    python and C++.
    It is gaining a lot of popularity and the community is getting bigger and bigger everyday.
    You can easilly install it here: https://www.tensorflow.org/install/
    Here you can see the popularity that it has gained:
    &lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/sg3pSH7.png&quot; alt=&quot;sg3pSH7.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/bjcOMEE.png&quot; alt=&quot;bjcOMEE.png&quot; /&gt;
    Scikit-learn, another big framework doesn’t support GPUs and is not really suitable 
    for neural networks (also want to note that most of their features were implemented 
    into Tensorflow  ;) ). It is free and also works with python, you can get more info and 
    installation instructions in their website: http://scikit-learn.org/stable/index.html&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Caffe
    Caffe is a big machine learning framework too, it’s written in c++ with a python interface.
     It is better suited for building applications (instead of Tensorflow which is developed for
     research and development). It’s not bad at all but I feel like Tensorflow is easier to use. This 
    is their homepage: http://caffe.berkeleyvision.org/&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/jzV6oUh.png&quot; alt=&quot;qSafFW8.png&quot; /&gt;
    Theano is one of the first frameworks created (it was created in 2007), it follows the 
    Tensorflow style, it does not support multi-GPU nor horizontal capabilities. It uses NumPy 
    to express computations. It is considered a low-end machine learnign frameworks but in 
    reality it’s is fast and flexible. Due to being old the docs are very well explained.
    Check it out here: http://deeplearning.net/software/theano/&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/xiaZq9p.png&quot; alt=&quot;xiaZq9p.png&quot; /&gt;
    Keras is object oriented and simple, it uses python and can be used with theano for best 
    performance (can be used with Tensorflow too but it doesn’t work that good).
    You can see a comparison of a sample of code of Keras with Tensorflow here:
    https://gist.github.com/ricgu8086/0ba44ce3aab19ec50425383a4d778b50
    For simple building get Keras, if you want more tweaks go to Tensorflow.
    Check it out here: https://keras.io/&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Uy00onV.png&quot; alt=&quot;Uy00onV.png&quot; /&gt;
    Torch is very famous too, however, it uses Lua, if you are into that go for it (it just 
    isn’t my case lol). It was used in facebook before they migrated to Tensorflow (if you 
    know what I mean).
    This is their website: http://torch.ch/&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;As you can see Tensorflow is the leading software now, it is one of the most powerful
     ones and not hard to master when you get the hang of it. Another big software is Keras, 
    if you just want to play around with deep learning it’s probably your option.&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/eWy9QyO.png&quot; alt=&quot;3ipRh6w.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Obviously this is just some theory; I plan on making more tutorials about machine 
    learning with real examples. However, if you are impatient I will leave you some good 
    links ;)&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;First of all we can find a defcon 25 talk where they apply machine learning for hacking, 
    it’s pretty interesting, in the talk they don’t explain anything about coding our model but 
    it will help you imagine how machine learning works better.
    https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wbRx18VZlYA&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Here you can find a lot of resources, there are books, websites, videos, etc.
    https://my.mindnode.com/k954FWFNztnkphWmNqqHz2dqQW41LeP1SLqkqqjs&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;I found out that a book that I am reading is free online, it’s not bad and it’s suitable 
    for university students. The online version is not exactly the same as the paper one, 
    but it is very useful.
    http://neuron.eng.wayne.edu/synapse2/tpage3.html&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;One of the most famous youtube channels about machine learning is Siraj Raval, he 
    studied computer science and works with python and TensorFlow, it’s a must-watch.
    https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCWN3xxRkmTPmbKwht9FuE5A&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;Sentdex is also a famous youtuber who makes coding videos, he also works with python,
     he has a very interesting project in my opinion: he made a car which drives itself in gta v 
    with machine learning (and he’s planning on adding even more AI to GTA so stay tunned guys haha).
    https://www.youtube.com/user/sentdex&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;This is one of my favourites youtubers, Carykh is a bit underrated and he should have way
     more subscribers in my opinion. Check him out and give it a follow, his videos are very 
    interesting and very well made :)
    https://www.youtube.com/user/carykh&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;There are way more videos and youtubers online but I think that with these links you can
    already have some fun!
    Hope you liked the tutorial and have fun :)&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://i.imgur.com/UBAPtJN.png&quot; alt=&quot;YjktbpY.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;https://www.analyticsvidhya.com/blog/2015/08/common-machine-learning-algorithms/&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;https://machinelearningmastery.com/a-tour-of-machine-learning-algorithms/&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Machine_learning&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;https://my.mindnode.com/k954FWFNztnkphWmNqqHz2dqQW41LeP1SLqkqqjs&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;https://www.codeproject.com/Articles/1104747/Introduction-to-Genetic-Algorithms-with-Python-Hel&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;https://www.analyticsvidhya.com/blog/2016/04/complete-tutorial-tree-based-modeling-scratch-in-python/&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Logistic_regression&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;https://en.coursera.org/learn/machine-learning/lecture/93VPG/k-means-algorithm&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apriori_algorithm&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Classification&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Regression_analysis&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;http://bigdata-madesimple.com/top-10-machine-learning-frameworks/&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;https://catalystsecure.com/blog/2017/07/deep-learning-in-e-discovery-moving-past-the-hype/&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;https://aircto.com/blog/everything-you-need-to-know-about-artificial-neural-network-deep-learning-part-i/&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;http://magizbox.com/training/machinelearning/site/ensemble/&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;http://www.kdnuggets.com/2016/08/10-algorithms-machine-learning-engineers.html/2&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;https://elitedatascience.com/machine-learning-algorithms&lt;/p&gt;
    
    &lt;p&gt;https://www.analyticsvidhya.com/blog/2015/09/naive-bayes-explained/&lt;/p&gt;</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /intro-to-machine-learning</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/intro-to-machine-learning</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Im using markdown</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;USING MARKDOWN LULZ
&lt;strong&gt;Get marked DOWN&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /welcome2</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/welcome2</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Dummy Page</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Proin non tortor dolor. Aliquam semper non est vel molestie. Donec urna tortor, tempus eget rhoncus vitae, luctus in lorem. Pellentesque vitae mi lectus. Mauris mattis 
    feugiat justo, sit amet aliquet justo suscipit eget. Vestibulum nec condimentum justo. Etiam vel diam convallis 
    lorem rhoncus finibus quis nec odio. Nullam a tortor sed turpis auctor tempor. Quisque in semper sem. Praesent ut velit ac tellus ullamcorper rhoncus. Sed dictum faucibus velit, eu cursus dui imperdiet ac. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2017 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /dummy-page</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/dummy-page</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Styles Showcase hehe xd</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;First p tag is a subheader so it is bigger hehe xd&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a  &lt;a href=&quot;/the-editor/&quot;&gt;very beautiful link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;specialformatting&quot;&gt;Special formatting id is big&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As well as bold and italics, you can also use some other special formatting in Markdown when the need arises, for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;s&gt;strike through&lt;/s&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;mark&gt;highlight&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;*escaped characters*&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;writingcodeblocks&quot;&gt;Writing code blocks&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two types of code elements which can be inserted in Markdown, the first is inline, and the other is block. Inline code is formatted by wrapping any word or words in back-ticks, &lt;code&gt;like this&lt;/code&gt;. Larger snippets of code can be displayed across multiple lines using triple back ticks:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;.my-link {
    text-decoration: underline;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you want to get really fancy, you can even add syntax highlighting using &lt;a href=&quot;http://prismjs.com/&quot;&gt;Prism.js&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fullbleedimages&quot;&gt;Full bleed images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One neat trick which you can use in Markdown to distinguish between different types of images is to add a &lt;code&gt;#hash&lt;/code&gt; value to the end of the source URL, and then target images containing the hash with special styling. For example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://casper.ghost.org/v1.0.0/images/walking.jpg#full&quot; alt=&quot;walking&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;which is styled with...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;img[src$=&amp;quot;#full&amp;quot;] {
    max-width: 100vw;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This creates full-bleed images in the Casper theme, which stretch beyond their usual boundaries right up to the edge of the window. Every theme handles these types of things slightly differently, but it's a great trick to play with if you want to have a variety of image sizes and styles.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;referencelists&quot;&gt;Reference lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The quick brown &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fox&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Fox&quot;&gt;fox&lt;/a&gt;, jumped over the lazy &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dog&quot; title=&quot;Wikipedia: Dog&quot;&gt;dog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way to insert links in markdown is using reference lists. You might want to use this style of linking to cite reference material in a Wikipedia-style. All of the links are listed at the end of the document, so you can maintain full separation between content and its source or reference.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;creatingfootnotes&quot;&gt;Creating footnotes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The quick brown fox&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn1&quot; id=&quot;fnref1&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; jumped over the lazy dog&lt;sup class=&quot;footnote-ref&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn2&quot; id=&quot;fnref2&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Footnotes are a great way to add additional contextual details when appropriate. Ghost will automatically add footnote content to the very end of your post.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;fullhtml&quot;&gt;Full HTML&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the best part of Markdown is that you're never limited to just Markdown. You can write HTML directly in the Ghost editor and it will just work as HTML usually does. No limits! Here's a standard YouTube embed code as an example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/Cniqsc9QfDo?rel=0&amp;amp;showinfo=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;hr class=&quot;footnotes-sep&quot;&gt;
&lt;section class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;ol class=&quot;footnotes-list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Foxes are red &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref1&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li id=&quot;fn2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-item&quot;&gt;&lt;p&gt;Dogs are usually not red &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref2&quot; class=&quot;footnote-backref&quot;&gt;↩︎&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ghost has a single, powerful organisational taxonomy, called tags.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It doesn't matter whether you want to call them categories, tags, boxes, or anything else. You can think of Ghost tags a lot like Gmail labels. By tagging posts with one or more keyword, you can organise articles into buckets of related content.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;basictagging&quot;&gt;Basic tagging&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you write a post, you can assign tags to help differentiate between categories of content. For example, you might tag some posts with &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; and other posts with &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt;, which would create two distinct categories of content listed on &lt;code&gt;/tag/news/&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;/tag/cycling/&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you tag a post with both &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt; &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - then it appears in both sections.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Tag archives are like dedicated home-pages for each category of content that you have. They have their own pages, their own RSS feeds, and can support their own cover images and meta data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;theprimarytag&quot;&gt;The primary tag&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Inside the Ghost editor, you can drag and drop tags into a specific order. The first tag in the list is always given the most importance, and some themes will only display the primary tag (the first tag in the list) by default. So you can add the most important tag which you want to show up in your theme, but also add a bunch of related tags which are less important.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, Bart Stevens, Extreme Sports&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this example, &lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt; is the primary tag which will be displayed by the theme, but the post will also still receive all the other tags, and show up in their respective archives.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&quot;privatetags&quot;&gt;Private tags&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes you may want to assign a post a specific tag, but you don't necessarily want that tag appearing in the theme or creating an archive page. In Ghost, hashtags are private and can be used for special styling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For example, if you sometimes publish posts with video content - you might want your theme to adapt and get rid of the sidebar for these posts, to give more space for an embedded video to fill the screen. In this case, you could use private tags to tell your theme what to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;&lt;strong&gt;News&lt;/strong&gt;, Cycling, #video&lt;/mark&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, the theme would assign the post publicly displayed tags of &lt;code&gt;News&lt;/code&gt;, and &lt;code&gt;Cycling&lt;/code&gt; - but it would also keep a private record of the post being tagged with &lt;code&gt;#video&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In your theme, you could then look for private tags conditionally and give them special formatting:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;nohighlight&quot;&gt;
    
        ...markup for a nice big video post layout...
    
        ...regular markup for a post...
    

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Sep 2012 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>
        /styles-showcase</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/styles-showcase</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
